<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CodingEconomist</title>
    <link>https://www.codingeconomist.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on CodingEconomist</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codingeconomist.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reading Nvidia SEC filings with the help of Natural Language Processing - Part II</title>
      <link>https://www.codingeconomist.com/post/reading_nvidia_sec_filings_with_nlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.codingeconomist.com/post/reading_nvidia_sec_filings_with_nlp/</guid>
      <description>How to analyze Nvidia SEC filings - Part II Introduction This series of articles is made of three parts. In part I of this series we explored frequency word count for the most common words in Nvidia SEC filings.
In this part, which is part II, we are going a step further, and try to explore the most important sentences from the company&amp;rsquo;s SEC filings.
The last part III of the series will explore comparison of SEC filing statements across different time periods and elimination of repeating sentences in order to narrow down the research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading Nvidia financial reports with the help of Natural Language Processing - Part I</title>
      <link>https://www.codingeconomist.com/post/reading_nvidia_financial_reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.codingeconomist.com/post/reading_nvidia_financial_reports/</guid>
      <description>How to analyze Nvidia financial report - Part I Introduction Reading financial reports of any company usually takes a lot of time. Even more time is required to compare financial reports across different years. According to some analysts, it may take months or even years of digging into company reports in order to get well acquainted with the company, and get a good understanding of its operations.
This is part one of a broader series of articles which will present the use of Natural Language Processing techniques for company financial reports analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The problem with Intel&#39;s SEC filings and NLP</title>
      <link>https://www.codingeconomist.com/post/problem_with_analyzing_intel_sec_filings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.codingeconomist.com/post/problem_with_analyzing_intel_sec_filings/</guid>
      <description>The Problem with Intel&amp;rsquo;s SEC filings and Natural Language Processing Objective The aim of this article was to show how chipmaker Intel Corporation makes use of their own 10-K form which differs substantially from the SEC 10-K, making automation of document reading much more difficult for analysts.
Methodology The main method used in this article is visual presentation and discussion.
Results In its latest 10-K SEC filing, Intel Corporation states as follows:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ether price vs Ethereum Gas price - more utility in the Ethereum network?</title>
      <link>https://www.codingeconomist.com/post/ethereum_price_vs_gas_price/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.codingeconomist.com/post/ethereum_price_vs_gas_price/</guid>
      <description>Comparison of Ether and Ethereum Gas prices Objective The aim of this article was to compare the prices of Ether and Ethereum Gas. Additionally an attempt was made at answering a question of whether Ethereum network is gaining more utility.
Methodology The main method used in this article is visual presentation and discussion. A program was written using python and jupyter lab environment to collect the relevant data and project it onto a graph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using NLP and SEC filings to explore hitech companies</title>
      <link>https://www.codingeconomist.com/post/analysis_of_new_technology_companies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.codingeconomist.com/post/analysis_of_new_technology_companies/</guid>
      <description>Analysis of hitech companies Introduction Recently a survey was conducted among participants of investing channel on reddit. The original poster asked redditors to name technologies and companies worth investing in, for future growth and profits. Responses among reddit users are usually open ended and vague, however several technologies were named, such as: biotechnology and genome sequencing, microchip production, micro nuclear reactors, solid state batteries, quantum computing and others.
Also, several publicly traded companies were named and their trading ticker was provided.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interest Rates and Stock Market - do rising interest rates harm the stock market?</title>
      <link>https://www.codingeconomist.com/post/fed_fund_rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.codingeconomist.com/post/fed_fund_rates/</guid>
      <description>Are rising interest rates bad for the stock market? Introduction On January 10th, Federal Reserve Chairman Powell spoke at the hearing, saying that the economy after the epidemic may be different from the previous expansion, the US labor market is strong, and policies must be considered forward-looking, and tools will be used to support the economy and employment. market. In fact, since the Fed released the early signal of raising interest rates last week, the market&amp;rsquo;s expectations for interest rate hikes in March have begun to rise sharply.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classification of market phases for crypto assets with HDBSCAN machine learning and PCA dimensions reduction method</title>
      <link>https://www.codingeconomist.com/post/hdbscan_analysis_crypto/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.codingeconomist.com/post/hdbscan_analysis_crypto/</guid>
      <description>Classification of market phases for crypto assets using HDBSCAN and PCA methods Introduction Market analysts employ a variety of statistical methods to classify market phases in order to develop investment strategies for different financial assets. Stock traders and derivatives traders usually have an arsenal of financial strategies (growth, flattening, butterflies) that they use depending on the current interest rate regime (i.e. when the Central Bank is easing or tightening its monetary policy).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differences between Cardano and Polkadot blockchains</title>
      <link>https://www.codingeconomist.com/post/cardano_vs_polkadot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.codingeconomist.com/post/cardano_vs_polkadot/</guid>
      <description>Comparison of Cardano and Polkadot and analysis of changes on Github Introduction Third generation blockchain. When we talk about third generation Blockchain networks, Cardano or Polkadot most often come to mind. But what is a third generation network, and what is meant by that? The classic first-generation network is Bitcoin. Ethereum with a consesus algorithm based on Proof of Work can be considered a second-generation network. A characteristic feature of the third generation network is the use of the Proof of Stake algorithm to confirm transactions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Correlation of selected crypto companies with Axie Infinity</title>
      <link>https://www.codingeconomist.com/post/axie_infinity_correlation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.codingeconomist.com/post/axie_infinity_correlation/</guid>
      <description>Correlation of selected crypto companies with Axie Infinity game tokens Introduction Canaan Inc and Riot Blockchain are two companies listed on the Nasdaq exchange, whose activities are related to Bitcoin mining. Canaan is a producer of specialized devices for high performance computing - called ASIC (application specific integrated circuit), used, among others, for calculations securing the Bitcoin network. Riot Blockchain is a mining company supporting Bitcoin blockchain by mining and securing networks on a large scale in the United States.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparable analysis of Uniswap vs Sushiswap vs Coinbase</title>
      <link>https://www.codingeconomist.com/post/valuation_of_uniswap_sushiswap_coinbase/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.codingeconomist.com/post/valuation_of_uniswap_sushiswap_coinbase/</guid>
      <description>Comparable valuation of cryptocurrency exchanges Uniswap, Sushiswap and Coinbase Introduction Coinbase is a Nasdaq listed company operating one of the largest centralized exchanges in the crypto industry. Unlike Coinbase, Uniswap and Sushiswap are not enterprises in the classic sense of the Commercial Companies Code.
Both Uniswap and Sushiswap are protocols that provide liquidity and allow automated trading of ERC-20 tokens with Ethereum. In other words, they are decentralized automatic exchanges operating on the Ethereum blockchain, abbreviated as DEX - (decentralized exchange).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Cardano?</title>
      <link>https://www.codingeconomist.com/post/what_is_cardano/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.codingeconomist.com/post/what_is_cardano/</guid>
      <description>What is Cardano? Part One.   Cardano is a very innovative blockchain, founded in 2015 by one of the founders of Ethereum, Charles Hoskinson. The premiere of Cardano began in earnest in 2017. Cardano is a Blockchain based on the Proof of Stake consensus algorithm. Contrary to Ethereum, which currently uses the Proof of Work mechanism. This means that you do not need huge amounts of electricity to confirm transactions, as is the case with Proof of Work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is DAO</title>
      <link>https://www.codingeconomist.com/post/what_is_dao/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.codingeconomist.com/post/what_is_dao/</guid>
      <description>What is DAO? DAO -  Decentralized Autonomous Organization  is an organization operating in accordance with the rules encoded as a computer program also known as a smart contract (smart contract). Think of it as a kind of company, registerd on blockchain that is run by smart contracts.
What is a smart contract? This is a self-executing contract where the terms between buyer and seller are written directly into the lines of code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.codingeconomist.com/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.codingeconomist.com/archives/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.codingeconomist.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.codingeconomist.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Who we are? We are a team of experienced economists and IT specialists with academic degrees. We have extensive competences in the field of sectoral analysis, fundamental analysis of companies and analysis of new technologies.
What we do? We analyze companies in the new technology industries. Such as biotech and IT. But that&amp;rsquo;s not everything. We are practitioners of smart contracts and blockchain. We carry out off-chain and on-chain analyzes, so we have first-hand access to data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://www.codingeconomist.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.codingeconomist.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>window.addEventListener(&#34;DOMContentLoaded&#34;, function() { var form = document.getElementById(&#34;contact-form&#34;); var button = document.getElementById(&#34;contact-form-button&#34;); var status = document.getElementById(&#34;contact-form-status&#34;); function success() { form.reset(); button.style = &#34;display: none &#34;; status.innerHTML = &#34;Your message has been sent&#34;; } function error() { form.reset(); button.style = &#34;display: none &#34;; status.innerHTML = &#34;Your message has been sent&#34;; } // handle the form submission event form.addEventListener(&#34;submit&#34;, function(ev) { ev.preventDefault(); var data = new FormData(form); ajax(form.method, form.action, data, success, error); }); }); // helper function for sending an AJAX request function ajax(method, url, data, success, error) { var xhr = new XMLHttpRequest(); xhr.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
