<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2022/05 on CodingEconomist</title>
    <link>https://www.codingeconomist.com/archives/2022/05/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2022/05 on CodingEconomist</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://www.codingeconomist.com/archives/2022/05/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Percentage loss from peak to bottom for crypto coins during 2022 bear market</title>
      <link>https://www.codingeconomist.com/post/percentage_loss_crypto_coins_during_bear_market/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.codingeconomist.com/post/percentage_loss_crypto_coins_during_bear_market/</guid>
      <description>Crypto is in a bear market. How did individual coins fare compared to one another? Introduction The crypto market is currently in a bear market (second quarter of 2022). Some analysts expect it to fall even lower, and according to others, the market has already hit the bottom.
As every crypto investor knows, the crypto market is not a monolith. It consists of many protocols with different utility. So at least in theory it should exhibit varied performance between different coins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading Nvidia SEC filings with SQL and Sentence Transformers - Part III</title>
      <link>https://www.codingeconomist.com/post/reading_nvidia_sec_filings_with_sql_and_transformers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.codingeconomist.com/post/reading_nvidia_sec_filings_with_sql_and_transformers/</guid>
      <description>How to analyze Nvidia SEC filings - Part III Introduction This series of articles is made of three parts. In part I of this series we explored frequency word count for the most common words in Nvidia SEC filings.
In part II we explored the most important sentences from the company&amp;rsquo;s SEC filings and we were overwhelmed by the number of them.
In the final part III of this series, will try to reduce the number of sentences to a more manageable position by eliminating repeating sentences from previous years in order to streamline the analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading Nvidia SEC filings with the help of Natural Language Processing - Part II</title>
      <link>https://www.codingeconomist.com/post/reading_nvidia_sec_filings_with_nlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.codingeconomist.com/post/reading_nvidia_sec_filings_with_nlp/</guid>
      <description>How to analyze Nvidia SEC filings - Part II Introduction This series of articles is made of three parts. In part I of this series we explored frequency word count for the most common words in Nvidia SEC filings.
In this part, which is part II, we are going a step further, and try to explore the most important sentences from the company&amp;rsquo;s SEC filings.
The last part III of the series will explore comparison of SEC filing statements across different time periods and elimination of repeating sentences in order to narrow down the research.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
